[The Ingenious One]
[Episode 3: A Fascinating Way Out of Danger]
Halt!
Mr. Su,
the road ahead is destroyed
and impassable.
Miss Shu,
the post road ahead is destroyed.
We need to delay for a while.
Mr. Su...
Cut the crap.
Jin.
I-I didn't say anything.
Am I so annoying to him?
I guess he’s still mad about the raw silk purchase yesterday.
Today is probably not gonna be a quiet day.
Sure.
Do you have a plan?
The sword is ruthless, while prowess is all that matters.
You two are my plan.
The truth you've been waiting for 15 years
is worse than you can imagine.
Love and hatred are all born from human hearts.
Only those who get rid of them can enter the Yuntai Sect.
Yun Xiang,
you still can't let it go.
And you still wanna investigate it, huh?
Luo is my family name.
I'm Luo Wenjia.
Do you feel cold?
We are like brothers.
So don't mind it.
What do you expect him to do?
He knew something would happen tonight,
while he still fell asleep in peace.
That makes me feel much better.
You should boast some martial arts skills.
If someone breaks in tonight,
do you need my help?
I've seen you use your moving technique.
Ordinary people couldn't have dodged those bolts.
To be honest with you,
once I use my moving technique,
you can't hurt me at all
even if you and Jin work together.
In this case,
why did you ask us to protect you?
Just because there's a little flaw in this moving technique.
For example?
How can I show my fatal flaw to others so easily?
Mr. Su,
come here to warm yourself up.
This
is enough.
You ruined my plan yesterday.
Take this as punishment.
I think, even if he didn't stop you,
the steward by your side
might not follow your wish either.
If I insisted,
Qian couldn't stop me.
The Su family has been the royal supplier for over a decade
as a big and wealthy clan.
You must be acting so absurdly
for some reason, right?
You thought you were smart and said something
to fulfill your own wish.
But what you said
will get others into a lot of trouble.
Then how about you explain it to us?
So I can know what I did wrong.
After my father passed away,
the Su family's business in the Nandu Chamber of Commerce
has been managed by my sister alone.
But I'm the only son of my father.
My sister wants me to take over it anxiously.
This time, I came to Yangzhou to buy silk.
Firstly,
she wanted me to gain some experience.
I did have some personal business,
and I wanted to make some money.
Well,
I was supposed to make a deal with them soon
and have some fun,
so my sister's wish could be fulfilled.
Who knew you'd get in the way?
The Su family is already the head of merchants.
Why don't you go into business?
Merchants... I've seen too many merchants.
Only two types of people will dig into business.
Profiteers,
and those who have no other way out.
So boring.
So you must be an ambitious person, Mr. Su.
Of course.
I aim to travel around the world with a sword.
If I can learn the best of all schools
and become a grand master,
isn't that good?
Shut up!
There come some villains!
Let's get closer.
Don't panic.
Martial arts are not learned with the mouth. Learn more skills.
Let's go.
Go after them!
Do not protect me.
Violators will be fined three months' wages.
Make way!
Catch up with her!
Qian.
Young Master,
you don't need to handle these guys.
What moving technique is this?
I've never seen it before.
He can make a way out when surrounded on all sides.
Looks like this guy wasn't bragging.
It's hard to break it even if the two of us work together.
How much longer do you wanna watch?
Just a little longer!
It's enough. Please stop.
If you force me to fight,
you will die for sure!
Help!
Help me!
The technique will stop working after ten breaths.
So this is the fatal flaw.
If you wanna test my martial arts,
I'll tell you after you ask me a few more times.
You don't have to kill me.
If I didn't go that far,
would you tell me honestly?
And you!
You didn't well protect your master, you know?
Does your useless technique have a name?
Run for Ten Breaths.
Pardon?
Run for Ten Breaths!
Mr. Yun,
have you ever seen these guys?
Mr. Qian, did you find out who these villains are?
As long as you're safe, Mr. Yun.
I saw it clearly tonight.
These people are not bandits.
They just targeted you.
If they were bandits,
they would have hidden by day and come out by night,
whose skin wouldn't be so dark.
Look.
Water ringworm.
They have solid shoulders and thick thighs.
It's caused by years of weight bearing.
Could they be the members of the Cao Sect?
The Cao Sect
could have safely escorted us to the Nandu Wharf.
But they kept refusing.
So we had to take this remote post road.
Mr. Yun,
do you have a grudge against the Cao Sect?
If you think this is the truth,
then just let it be.
Jin,
your swordplay looks so fierce.
I once thought you inherited it from the Wu family in Nandu.
But the Wus' swordplay, Twelve Hanging-rock Techniques,
is mainly about flawless attacks,
not winning by speed.
But I saw you attacking three persons
at lightning speed.
I'm just a swordsman. I have nothing to do with the inheritance.
I just have travelled a lot and seen a lot.
You're right.
Your swordplay
boasts the trait of the Liu family in Yuezhou.
But the Lius' swordplay
is like a steady downpour of rain.
What's the point of these fancy names?
The swordplay
is used to kill people.
Nope, Jin.
Knowing yourself and your enemy, you can fight a hundred battles and win them all.
Your swordplay seems quite sharp,
but it's not flawless.
Not flawless?
Go ahead.
This sword
isn't used to win by speed.
Your swordplay is similar to the Downpour Swordplay
of the Liu family.
It seems that the point is the sword.
But in fact, the power comes from the legs.
From the legs to the waist, then to the hands, then to the sword.
So to use this Downpour Swordplay,
the point is to protect the lower body.
But when you use it, you move a lot
and completely ignore the defence...
Forget it...
No one has seen through it, while you pointed it out.
Well...
You just kept talking without fighting anyone.
Jin! Jin!
It's not that I don't wanna help you.
I just thought...
I didn't expect you to be really capable like that.
Miss Shu.
By the way,
the swordplay you use
seems so tricky,
but indeed it's all about defence, not attack.
When the enemy's defence is broken,
you'll give them a fatal blow.
It reminds me of Nandu Shu family's Altair Swordplay.
Yes.
Are you dumb?
Isn't her surname Shu?
Just a coincidence.
I guess so.
I heard that there's no inheritor
of the Shu family's swordplay now.
But your moving technique is also amazing.
I think I've seen it somewhere before.
It seems to be the lost technique of the Golden Wing Secret Agent in the previous dynasty.
Right, here you are.
Mr. Su,
when will the caravan depart?
Miss Shu, Jin,
we really hit it off, and it's a pleasure chatting with you.
When we arrive in Nandu, let me treat you
to something interesting.
Nice...
I've been there several times, but I've never done much sightseeing yet.
Good idea.
Then that's a deal.
-Okay. -Okay.
Hurry up!
[Nice Weather]
This way! Here!
Lend me a hand!
Chief Zhang,
how can you apologize to your master?
Master, I underestimated him.
I didn't expect him to be surrounded by top martial arts masters.
The tea house just sent it to us.
They said the tea leaves were picked this morning.
I guess you'll like it.
How many of our men died?
S-Seventeen.
Bury them well.
Yes, Master.
Master,
please give me one more chance
to make up for my mistake.
If I fail,
I'll kill myself for it.
Zhang Kui,
this is the last time.
He's dead.
We've verified it.
It's true.
-Mr. Qian. -Mr.Qian.
Where is our lady?
In the backyard study.
My lady.
[Su Huairou from the Su Family in Nandu]
You've brought back the raw silk, huh?
Yes, we've brought it all back
and stored it in the Yufeng Warehouse.
Thank you for your hard work.
My lady,
why didn't you wait for me
to come back and handle this tiring work?
If I didn't calculate it myself today,
I wouldn't know how hard your work is.
My lady,
you've been so engaged in the affairs of the Chamber of Commerce.
So please don't waste your time
on the chores of our mansion.
Where's Mingyu? Why hasn't he come back?
[Liansheng House]
Liansheng House?
So magnificent.
Mr. Su, so the first stop on your return
is a gambling house.
Mr. Su, you have such a wide range of hobbies.
Why are you still following us?
Stop arguing. It's a waste of time.
Let's go...
Go...
Let's go inside to take a look.
Mr. Su,
there are so few people here.
Why don't you find a more bustling place to have fun?
Please forgive me, Jin.
To be honest with you,
this Liansheng House is gonna be auctioned tomorrow.
I'm just in a hurry to meet a friend of mine.
Gambling is the same wherever you are.
[Ke Menglan from the Liansheng House]
Guys,
place and finalize your bets.
All in.
Mr. Qi, are you skipping this round?
The Liansheng House will be auctioned tomorrow.
You'd better think carefully.
Mr. Qi, as I told you,
eleven on the left, and eleven on the right.
It's a draw.
The banker takes all.
-I lost again... -I lost again.
You still have a few hours to think about it.
If nothing was gonna change in the Liansheng House,
I wouldn't have persuaded you to follow me.
But the Tangs' Gambling House has already said,
if you're auctioned off to the Tang family,
then...
I want your seat.
Are you kidding me?
It's you, Mr. Su.
Sit down please,
Mr. Su.
Jin.
Here you are.
Okay.
This girl looks so beautiful.
I haven't gambled for days.
I quite miss it.
Menglan,
Jin is my friend.
Please go easy on him.
Nonsense!
When did I ever lose?
Girl, don't listen to him!
Just show me what you've got.
Do you know this Liansheng House
used to be Godfather's property?
Come on...
Place the bet here.
Where to place the bet?
I choose this!
It's rare to have a place to relax.
Why do you have so much on your mind?
I'm wondering
why Su Mingyu
happened to bring us here.
Don't bother thinking about it.
A day without her
can make him miss her like crazy.
The story between a young master of a noble family and a female croupier in a gambling house.
Sounds great in a novel,
but it's hard in real life.
Godfather owned businesses
all over Nandu in his prime.
It was so glorious.
But once he lost power,
the merchants in Nandu were like wolves devouring a tiger.
Soon, this Liansheng House became the only one left.
Even this will also disappear, I'm afraid.
Not necessarily.
What does saving Liansheng House have to do
with your revenge?
What exactly is the purpose of your trip this time?
Miss Shu,
can you first tell me
who is qualified to learn the moving technique
of the Golden Wing Secret Agent in the previous dynasty?
As far as I know, this technique can only be learned...
Yes, only in the Lingyuan Sect.
You admit that you're a Lingyuan rebel?
Three years ago, I once travelled to Ganzhou
and saved a dying Lingyuan Sect member.
The secret skills of the Lingyuan Sect are never passed on to outsiders.
He probably tried to lure me to join the Lingyuan Sect.
Did you
learn their martial arts
and then find a chance to run away?
Exactly.
Wait.
Haven't you been determined to take revenge on Qi Tianfeng?
Why didn't you join them
after you learned the skills of the Lingyuan Sect?
Your Yuntai Sect has a feud with the Lingyuan Sect.
If I joined the Lingyuan Sect,
how could I face Godfather again?
Flawless.
The imperial court also sees the Yuntai Sect as a big threat,
while you didn't hide your identity at all.
It makes me sort of suspicious.
What?
If you wanted to turn me in, you wouldn't have waited until today.
Why do you think I have mercy on you?
You have both eyes for me.
See more carefully now.
The figure is slightly distorted,
but the face is still outstanding.
Don't flatter yourself.
No girls will like your words.
Are you playing tricks with me?
Jin,
take a rest if you have bad luck for now.
Wait.
Why didn't you place any bets
after I got to the table?
We wanna tell the trend through you, of course.
Bro, although you look kind of silly,
you're so strong.
Girl,
can I pay on credit?
We usually don't allow that.
But since you're Mr. Su's friend...
No, Menglan.
Stay out of this.
Jin, you lost 30 taels.
Then I can give you 30 taels on credit,
until you win them back. How about that?
Wonderful!
He's fond of gambling but not good at it.
That's really a vice.
I was just thinking about how to keep him by my side.
This is a good chance.
You wanna take advantage of his weakness, yet you sound so proud.
Are all the Yuntai members
so shameless?
Use some shameless tricks
to achieve something great and honorable.
This is similar to how you learned
the martial arts of the Lingyuan Sect.
You've come for more than revenge, right?
Yes,
or not.
You're full of lies.
You want me to team up with you?
Just forget about that.
Sir and Madam, please have some tea first.
Just leave this to me.
Don't come unless I ask you to.
Thank you, sir.
Miss,
you're really smart.
You're right.
I do have other plans.
But I wasn't lying when I proposed
to deal with Qi Tianfeng.
How can I trust you?
Within this month,
I'll destroy Qi Tianfeng
and his Cao Sect.
Your departure or stay is up to you.
But if you decide to join hands with me,
I need you to promise me one thing.
Go ahead.
You and I do our part and complement each other.
But please don't ask the reason
for my commission.
When it's done,
if you still don't understand,
I'll explain it to you.
Deal.
But I have a blood feud.
If you change your mind halfway,
your Run for Ten Breaths,
or even Run for A Hundred Breaths...
I know.
You'll show me no mercy.
When did you ever show mercy?
You deserve it for talking nonsense.
No more jokes. Let's get down to business.
Now, the merchants in Nandu
are ready to divide up Mr. Wen's business.
But you should know that
it's usually about a series of debts in business.
There were some debts Mr. Wen owed them,
and some they owed Mr. Wen, of course.
Are you gonna collect all the debts?
Exactly. Thank you, Miss.
But Mr. Wen has passed away.
Who would admit their debts?
That depends on your tactics.
This thing matters a lot.
There's no time to waste.
You'd better set off right away.
You may soon run into lots of hard nuts to crack.
Be careful.
What's the use of just talking?
How about we go together?
Jin,
black or red?
Black or red?
You tell me!
How would I know?
So useless!
Still red!
Okay.
Hold on!
Let me take a closer look.
Black, 14.
18, 18, 18...
18, 18, 18!
Red, 12.
Black wins.
Sir,
you lost and borrowed 60 taels in total.
If you lose all the money, do you need our help?
I'm gonna kill you, you know?
Don't worry, Jin.
You still have me to cover
your daily expenses these days.
You lost and borrowed 60 taels of gold in total, huh?
How long do you have to stay in the Sus' mansion
to make up for this money?
Why are you so sarcastic again?
Mr. Su,
you brought Jin to the gambling house
on the first stop in Nandu, huh?
You two set me up!
Jin, I didn't.
Jin, you must be joking.
In front of everyone,
I
dare not gamble with the reputation of the Liansheng House.
Yeah.
You don't need to play any tricks against him.
I'm gonna kill you if you insult me again,
for free.
It's 60 taels of gold,
the money for killing 6 people.
Are you willing to donate it to the gambling house for nothing?
Who on earth are you siding with?
Miss,
I still have 60 taels left.
Can I play a game with you?
Just one round to decide the winner.
Let's bet on the 60 taels of gold he just lost.
How do you want to play it?
You and I each hold a cup.
If we get the same number after the opening, I win.
If not, you win.
How about that?
Menglan, don't play it with him.
This man's so cunning.
Okay, let's play as you say.
Guys,
please keep quiet.
This gambling game
all depends on listening.
Thank you.
After you, Miss.
It's your turn, sir.
I'm done.
Can that work?
-He didn't shake it! -He didn't
even shake it!
Red, 10
It's 10.
Black...
You are so lucky, sir.
I lost.
Jin.
How many more unique skills do you have?
Yun Xiang! Yun Xiang!
Yun Xiang!
Fragrant bags, sachets, and pendants.
Give that to me. You've kept it for a long time.
What?
My 30 taels of gold!
Are you kidding me?
I won that money with my skill.
Besides, I even removed your debt
of 30 taels of gold.
You...
Jin,
as a great warrior,
you won't play dumb with me, will you?
Do you have any enemies?
I'll kill a few for you, at half price.
Then how about this?
You condescend to follow me for some days,
and I pay you 1 tael of gold every day, huh?
You tricked me.
I know you've worked so hard
in the past few days.
Take this money,
and find an inn to have a good rest.
What do you mean?
You don't need me now?
I hope you get killed by the Cao Sect!
[Servant Girl, Tianhu]
Are you worried about the auction?
We'll know the result tomorrow.
Now, the only person we can rely on
is Mr. Su.
Menglan.
Don't be sad.
The auction is tomorrow.
No matter how much you win today, it's hard to change the situation.
I know, of course.
I just want Tianhu and the others
to lead a better life.
Tang Xiao can't take Liansheng House away
Look, I've saved 3,000 taels of silver.
I'm sure I can win it at tomorrow's auction.
Thank you for your kindness, Mr. Su.
But could you please be more prudent when you say anything in the future?
You once promised you'd ask Chairman Su
to stop Tang Xiao from bidding.
Did you do it?
-Menglan... -I guess you tried,
but Chairman Su refused.
I know you don't mind my menial background.
But how can the Su family accept it?
So please
don't waste your time, sir.
Menglan. Menglan!
Time will prove my sincerity.
Tomorrow...
I'll protect Liansheng House tomorrow.
[Guanghui Bank]
Please keep it well.
I wanna deposit this.
Liu,
are you here to deposit money again?
This way, please.
Please.
Mr. Wang, this way, please.
This way, please.
Sir, we only do business with regular customers on the list.
No deposit or withdrawal for other customers.
I do have an account here.
Our Guanghui Bank deposits money for many major merchants in Nandu.
There's a large number of them,
[Kang Qiao from the Yuntai Sect]
but I've never seen you before, sir.
May I have your account name?
No.1 of Qian.